Now I will take an example. The first claim comes in. If there is an
accident and hospitalization is required,
what will happen?
You can claim from your health insurance policy as well. If you
want, you can
also claim from your personal accidental insurance policy.
Accident happened. You were admitted to the hospital. You were admitted for
five days. You came home and got
discharged. Now what
happened after that? The doctor said you are on bed rest. You had
surgery on your leg and you
cannot go to work for six weeks. What
happened here? There will be a disability, total temporary
disability. Now what happened here? You are
not able to go to work for six weeks. So the
health insurance policy will not give you anything in this because the
health insurance policy had to pay
your hospitalization expenses,
which it has paid. Now after that, the role of
personal accidental insurance will come.
If you have taken personal accidental insurance, then
there you get weekly benefit.
₹0000 per week depending on
the policy and sum insured. So, you
get weekly benefit for the time you are on
bed rest.  Suppose the doctor
says that you will be put on bed rest for six weeks,
your mobility
is restricted, you are not able to go to work
and there is loss of income, then for that time
you will get weekly benefit, whatever is there
in your policy, compensation of ₹50,000 or ₹1 lakh per week,
so if we assume ₹1 lakh per week, then
you can take that as per ₹1 lakh per week,
you will get an additional payout of ₹1 lakh
from your personal accidental policy, this
is over and above your hospitalization
expenses, that is why it is said that a personal
accidental policy should be taken separately, now
here we assume that if there is any
disability, suppose there is any
permanent disability or any
partial disability, then
what will happen in that case, your health insurance
policy will not pay, they will cure you and
send you home, but after that,
after the disability, many expenses
increase, so your personal
accidental policy will pay for it if you have taken it.  If so, then
that health insurance policy will not give it. Now let's take
another example of health insurance
and critical illness. Suppose you have a
health insurance policy of 10 lakhs and a
critical illness insurance policy of 10
lakhs. Now here a cancer claim has come for example because
cancer is the most common critical illness and is diagnosed and
due to cancer, suppose a surgery is done, then
your health insurance
policy has a limit of 10 lakhs,
so the surgery cost, chemotherapy and other medical
expenses will be covered by your health insurance policy.
Now if you have
taken a critical illness insurance policy and there,
now suppose cancer is in the list
of critical illnesses, then
10 lakhs. The
critical
condition was that if these listed illnesses are
diagnosed, then we will give you a lump sum amount. As per the
policy terms and conditions,
you will get a lump sum of ₹10 lakhs over and
above your hospitalization expenses. So, whatever the
hospital expenses are,  And on
top of that, your critical illness policy will
give you because your most asked question is
whether
critical illnesses are not covered in my policy, is
accidental
hospitalization not covered in my policy, it is absolutely
covered, so these are over and now fixed
benefit policies, if you want more benefits,
if that incident happens then you
get more benefits, then it
is necessary to take these additional policies and my suggestion from my side will be
that these policies are important, not only just
health insurance, in today's date
accidents are increasing, critical
illness, you are hearing that every second or third
house has a critical illness, so if you have a critical
illness policy then you will get a lump payout, there are
many such expenses
which cannot be met in the hospital and even later
your earning capacity reduces,
your expenses increase, so it is necessary for you to have a
FinanciallyExpress
accidental policy and a critical illness
policy.